James Wang

6-8 Pottinger St, Central, Hong Kong • james.wang.dev712@gmail.com

Web developer

7 years of web development experience. Implemented responsive design principles to ensure mobile compatibility of websites and maintained databases such as MySQL or Mongo. In 8 months improved and maintained web apps using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, React and Next.js. This process increased number of 5-star UX/UI reviews by 135%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hong Kong Ops Technology Limited • 08/2020 - 07/2022 Senior Web Developer

- Implemented responsive design principles to ensure mobile compatibility of 3 websites in 4 months.
- Communicated project status to primary stakeholders and project management personnel for 2 projects in 3 months.
- Completed programming projects that complied with existing coding standards and design styles and improved user satisfaction by 37%.
- Developed web platform that increased user conversion rate by 25% in 3 months.

Lm International Trading Co • 05/2018 - 08/2020 Web Developer

- Maintained databases such as MySQL or Mongo for storing dynamic data used by 3 websites and increased the performance by 31%.
- Maintained understanding of current web technologies and programming practices through continuing education and participation in professional conferences and workshops in 5 months.
- Developed and maintained web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery.

Crawford House • Hong Kong, Hong Kong • 07/2017 - 03/2018

Junior Web Developer

- Developed wireframes, site maps and content inventories for new website designs increase target audience engagement by 14% in 4 months.
- Applied emerging technologies to update and maintain site applicability. Built website interfaces with HTML and CSS for 3 websites.
- Spearheaded the development of dynamic web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React; increased user engagement by 25% boost in customer retention.

EDUCATION

B Sc Computer Science

City University Of Hong Kong • Hong Kong, Hong Kong • 04/2013 - 05/2017

SKILLS

React, Next.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, TypeScript